how to practically
contemplate a nature without
going into abstractions without you know
floating away into abstract theories
about what a nature is
well the practical way and pretty much
the only way because the abstract
contemplation of a niche is not their
nature is to to find things
is to to find things
that are dear to you
including yourself your own senses
your own possessions people family
relatives and then contemplate their
cessation and you're
that's why nietzsche leads to dukkha to
recognition of dukkha
not any personal scientific anichia
well look everything is changing that i
don't care about
so find things you care about and start
applying the notion of impermanence that
you know
to those things and you will feel dukkha
and that you realize that's the
necessary base for the practice that's
where practice begins
and that's it so you can make a
contemplation out of it
so it's not about you know someone can
look at the word anitra and then
you know find the etymology of it and go
into the pali about it
yeah if you don't know what what what a
niche is
then yeah that can help you give you the
idea the context of the impermanence but
if you want to practice that on each
other not just get the right information
about it
then you need to find things that you
are emotionally
connected with and start seeing it there
because it's a nietzsche dukkha and then
the experience of anato if you
understand that but
yeah there is a reason that's kind of
the universal principle because
people don't see a niche which is why
they don't see the
of the same thing so in order to see the
dukkha which is necessary for the right
which is necessary for the right
practice you need to start seeing the
anichia on the level of things that you are
on the level of things that you are
pretty much
attached to that mean to you so don't
just take
impersonal pondering and contemplation
but actually find stuff that you would
be affected if it changes
that's it and then think about that and
allow that in your mind to endure
and see it's like wait but it will
change one way or the other
so why am i ignoring this obvious
reality of of things that are dear to me
of of things that are dear to me
and that's that's already the right
practice or certainly closer to the
right practice
than if you were to just study and and
think about a niche and use anita
as a kind of explanatory principles like
yes everything is constantly changing as
the buddha and modern scientists have
shown look const this this wood is constantly
look const this this wood is constantly
electrons are constantly moving and
that's constantly changing
that's irrelevant that's not the nature
that's just you applying an external
theory that you adopted and it please
and it pleases you no just imagine like
what if i were to go blind
what if i were to lose my eyesight would
i be affected
would i grieve what if i were to become
i don't know injured and i can't move
anymore would i be emotionally affected
yes ah so i'm attached to the body to
the movement to the senses
but they will fade they will change i
will lose my sight
so why am i ignoring that and there is
no right answer
what about thinking like oh but why is
everything in nature let's get down to
the why
sure sure yeah that that's kind of often
mine would go in those directions but
that's like when you
that's what buddha said when you go into
the directions of trying to find out
who and why they shot you with an arrow
instead of finding out how to get the
arrow out and cure yourself from the
wound so those questions you need to restrain
so those questions you need to restrain
because they're kind of pointless
and they still revolve around the same
craving and you would use
the information that you will get
through the answer of why
to basically lull yourself back into
thinking okay now you dealt with the
nature because you found the reason for
it
no the only way to deal with the niche
is not to get the right answer to what a
nietzsche is or why the it on each is
there is to not be affected by it when it
is to not be affected by it when it
occurs
when the change happens will i remain
imperturbable the only way to be imperturbable in
the only way to be imperturbable in
regard to niche is to practice
immovability in regard to niche and to
not ignore it
not to find the right answer for it but
yes sometimes finding more answers about
it will make you think about on each and
more will make you reflect the most it's
not necessarily always bad
but yes don't fall into the trap of
thinking that providing answers and
satisfactory explanations of why on each
is there
somehow made you closer to understanding
it it's not
if your mind doesn't move on account of
it that's what makes you closer to understanding